翻译：草草哭成傻逼
校对：草草爱瑞秋女神
时间轴：薛定谔的猫  大喷子  芝麻圆子
时间轴：芒果树叶  兜兜兜爹
总监：somehacker
后期：bongpong
瑞恩·高斯林
瑞秋·麦克亚当斯
詹姆斯·加纳
吉娜·罗兰兹
恋恋笔记本
改编自尼古拉斯·斯帕克斯小说
打扰
Excuse me.
来吧  亲爱的  准备上床吧
Come on, honey, let's get you ready for bed.
导演  尼克·卡索维茨
我这人没什么特别
I am no one special...
就是个普通人  有普通的心思
...just a common man with common thoughts.
我的生活也很普通
I've led a common life.
没有人为我建纪念碑
There are no monuments dedicated to me.
不久  我的名字也将被世人遗忘
And my name will soon be forgotten.
但在一方面
But in one respect...
我的成功不逊于任何人
...I've succeeded as gloriously as anyone who ever lived.
-气色不错啊  公爵  -感觉也不错
- Looking good, Duke. - Feeling good.
我全心全意地爱过另一个人
I've loved another with all my heart and soul...
对我而言  这辈子做到这点就足够了
...and for me that has always been enough.
你好吗  哈利
How's it hanging, Harry?
我一直想死掉  他们就是不许
I keep trying to die, but they won't let me.
哪能事事顺心呢
Well, you can't have everything.
今天很重要
Big day today.
你每天都这么说  老不正经
You say that every day, you old devil.
今天外面天气很好
It's a lovely day outside.
我们去散散步吧
Let's take a walk.
还是不了
I don't think so.
你得出屋啊
Well, we've got to get you out of this room.
走吧  亲爱的
Come on now, honey.
呼吸下新鲜空气对你有好处
Some fresh air would do you good.
你们好
Hello.
抱歉  今天她状况不太好
I'm sorry, it's not a good day.
我看她什么也不想做
I don't think she's up for anything.
你好
Hello?
这是公爵  他是来给你念书的
This is Duke, he's come to read to you.
念书
Read?
嗯  还是算了吧
No. I don't know.
去吧  你会喜欢他的  他可逗了
Oh, come on, you'll like him. He's very funny.
好了  上次说到哪了
All right, now, where did we leave off?
对了  嘉年华的那个晚上
Oh, yeah, yeah, it was the night of the carnival.
诺亚跟他朋友芬恩和莎拉一起去了
Noah was there with his friends Fin and Sara.
-诺亚  -他们就是在那儿遇见的
- Noah? - That's where they met.
1940年6月6日
June 6th, 1940.
艾莉那年才17岁
Allie was 17 years old.
-小伙子拿到奖品喽  -该死
- Little man wins a prize. - Damn!
-多谢参与  -你怎么不去说相声
- Thank you for playing. - Ha, you're real funny.
我就是没使劲而已
Man, I clobbered that thing.
告诉你  这种游戏都做手脚了
I'm telling you, these games are fixed.
你好啊
Hello.
你叫什么
Hi, what's your name?
跟莎拉一起的女孩是谁
Who's this girl with Sara?
艾莉·汉密尔顿
Her name's Allie Hamilton.
跟家人来这儿过暑假的
She's here for the summer with her family.
她爸比上帝还有钱
Dad's got more money than God.
-芬恩  -嘿  亲爱的
- Hi, Fin! - Hi, honey.
我给你赢了个奖品哦
Look, I won you a prize.
芬恩  谢谢
Oh, Fin, thank you!
艾莉  吃棉花糖吗
Hey, Allie, you want some cotton candy?
好啊
Um, okay.
-想跟我跳舞吗  -不想
- You want to dance with me? - No.
-为什么  -就是不想
- Why not? - Because I don't want to.
诺亚  她跟我们一起的
Noah, she's with us.
艾莉  要去坐摩天轮吗
Hey, Allie, you wanna ride the Ferris wheel?
-好啊  -走吧
- I'd love to. - All right.
借过
Excuse me.
-诺亚·卡尔霍恩  -什么
- Noah Calhoun. - What?
跟芬恩一起在贮木场工作
Works down at the lumberyard with Fin.
你看到了吗  他站得离我那么近
Did you see he was standing like two inches away from my face?
看到了  诺亚就这样
Yeah, I saw. That's Noah, though.
没想到他会主动过来  八成是看上你了呢
You know, I'm surprised he even came over. I think he likes you.
-你干什么  混蛋  -放开我
- Hey, what...? Jerk! - Get off me.
-你这是干什么  -你不能那么做
- What are you doing? - Hey, you can't do that!
我下去给钱  汤米
I'll pay you when I get down, Tommy.
我是诺亚·卡尔霍恩
I'm Noah Calhoun.
-那又如何  -见到你很高兴
- So? - So it's really nice to meet you.
艾莉  这人是谁
Allie, who is this guy?
不认识啊  诺亚·卡尔霍恩
I don't know. Noah Calhoun.
我真的很想约你出去
I would really like to take you out.
伙计  你自觉点行吗
Friend! Do you mind?
一张椅子上不能超过两个人  诺亚
You can't sit more than two people in a chair, Noah.
好吧  汤米
Okay, Tommy, all right.
快下来  诺亚  你要害死自己了
Get down, Noah, you're gonna kill yourself!
诺亚  别闹了
Noah, cut it out.
你现在愿意跟我约会了吗
Now, will you go out with me?
什么
What?
-不要  -不
- No. - No?
-不  -不吗
- No! - No?
-伙计  她都说了  -为什么啊
- Hey, pal, she just told you. - Why not?
不知道  就是不想呗
I don't know, because I don't want to.
诺亚
Noah!
好吧  那我没办法了
All right. Well, you leave me no other choice then.
-天呐  -我不是开玩笑的  诺亚
- Oh, my God. - I'm not kidding. Noah.
-别闹了  -你这是干什么啊
- Stop fooling around. - What are you doing?
-诺亚  抓稳杆子  -我再问一遍
- Noah, grab the bar. - I'm gonna ask you one more time.
你愿意
Will you...
还是不愿意跟我约会
...or will you not go out with me?
诺亚  你疯了吗  行了
Noah, are you nuts? Come on
该死  我手在发滑
Goddamn, my hand's slipping.
那就抓住杆子啊  蠢货
Then grab the bar, you idiot.
-除非她同意  -就跟他约会吧  亲爱的
- Not until she agrees. - Ah, go on out with him, honey.
-好吧  我跟你约会  -什么
- Okay, okay, fine, I'll go out with you. - What?
-不  别可怜我  -不不  我是真心想去
- No, don't do me any favors. - No, no. I want to.
-你想去  -对
- You want to? - Yes!
-说出来  -我想跟你去约会
- Say it. - I want to go out with you.
-再说一遍  -我想跟你去约会
- Say it again. - I want to go out with you!
好嘛  好嘛  那就去吧
All right, all right, we'll go out.
你自以为很聪明  是吗
You think you're so smart, don't you?
这可不好笑  诺亚  你个蠢货
That wasn't funny, Noah, you idiot!
没事  我能应付他
No, it's okay, I'll take care of this.
你干什么
What are you doing?
别这么做
Please don't do that.
别这样  艾莉  真难以置信
Please don't do that, Allie. I can't believe it.
天呐
Oh, God.
现在得瑟不起来了吧
You're not so cocky now, are you?
等我回头收拾你的
I'm gonna get you for that.
或许吧  或许不会
Oh, maybe you will, maybe you won't.
快看啊
Oh, yeah, will you look at that?
那不是嘉年华那个姑娘吗
It's that girl from the carnival, right?
还记得我吗
Do you remember me?
记得啊  内裤先生  是吧
Yeah, sure. Mr. Underwear, was it?
-是啊  -怎么忘得掉啊
- Oh, yeah. - How could I forget?
我想跟你澄清一下
I wanted to clear that up with you.
那天的事我很抱歉
Cause, I'm really sorry about that.
真是太蠢了
It was a really stupid thing to do,
爬到摩天轮上跟人搭讪
crawl up a Ferris wheel to talk to somebody.
但我必须靠近你
But I had to be next to you.
我完全被你吸引了
I was being drawn to you.
天呐  好会调情啊
Oh, jeez, what a line!
你对谁都这么说吗
You use that on all the girls?
-不是的  -是嘛
- No. - Right.
我那晚看见你跟戴缎带的女孩在一起了
I saw you the other night with Little Miss Ribbons.
-你今晚有事吗  -什么
- What are you doing tonight? - What?
或者明晚  这周末  都行啊
Or tomorrow night, or this weekend, whatever.
-干什么  -我们的约会啊
- Why? - Why? Our date.
什么约会
What date?
-你答应我的约会啊  -没有
- The date that you agreed to. - No.
你答应了  你还发誓了
Yes, you did. You promised and you swore it.
那我就是改主意了
Well, I guess I changed my mind.
我明白的  一个脏兮兮的男人
Look, I know you get some dirty guy
在大街上跑上来跟你搭话
coming up to you on the street.
你又不认识他  你不了解我  但我了解我
You don't know him. You don't know me, but I know me.
我要是看上了什么东西  就...一心一意
And when I see something that I like, I gotta... I love it.
我会如痴如狂
I go... I mean, I go crazy for it.
你说什么呢
Okay, what are you talking about?
你啊
Well, you.
-你真厉害  -什么
- Oh, you're good. - What?
-真会说话啊  -不是的
- You're good. - No.
-真是高手啊  -你误解我了
- You're good. - No, you're getting me wrong.
-简直神了  -不是的
- You're fantastic. - I'm not.
真的  我佩服死了
You really are. I'm impressed.
-我通常不是这样的  抱歉  -你就是
- I'm not usually like this, I'm sorry. - Oh, yes, you are.
如果你喜欢  我也可以很风趣的
I can be fun, if you want.
或者忧郁  机灵
Pensive. Uh, smart.
迷信  勇敢
Uh, superstitious, brave.
我还挺会跳舞
And, uh, I can be light on my feet.
随你喜欢
I could be whatever you want.
告诉我你喜欢什么  我就能做到
You just tell me what you want and I'll be that for you.
你真傻
You're dumb.
这也行啊
I could be that.
就一次约会嘛  有什么大不了的
Come on, one date. What's it gonna hurt?
不行
Mm, I don't think so.
我要怎么让你改主意啊
Well, what can I do to change your mind?
你总会想到的
Guess you'll figure something out.
你确定她会来吗
You sure she's coming?
放松  伙计  都安排好了
Relax, pal, it's all set up.
我们跟她们碰面看夜场电影  看
We're meeting her for the late show. Look.
我说什么来着  来吧
What did I tell you? Come on.
天呐  好巧啊
Oh, my goodness, what a coincidence!
看看谁来了  艾莉  你还记得诺亚吧
Look who's here! Allie, you remember Noah, don't you?
-记得  -是吗
- Yes, I remember. - Yeah?
-过来  -芬恩
- Come here. - Fin.
-很高兴又见到你了  -我也是
- It's nice to see you again. - You too.
-你真美  -谢谢
- You look great. - Oh, thanks.
真的好美
Really, really great.
你是挺美  你也够帅
You do look great. You look great.
我知道我是玉树临风  那我们能去看电影了吗
And I know I look great, so could we please go see this movie?
就要开始了
The show's about to start.
你先请
After you.
给我回来  莱尔·阿布纳
You come back here, Li'l Abner.
漫画改编电影《莱尔·阿布纳》  实为40年11月上映
别想抓到我黛茜·梅
You ain't gonna catch me, Daisy Mae!
今天是萨迪·霍金斯日  我就是该抓住你的
It's Sadie Hawkins Day, I'm supposed to catch you!
我比你快
I'm faster than you.
快过来
Get up here!
不要啊
No! No!
我抓住你
I'll get you!
来啊
Go on, get!
我来喽
Here I come!
你正大光明地抓住了"臭鼬"
You catch Polecat fair and square.
等等我
Wait for me.
刚刚的电影都讲什么了
What happened in that movie?
-有请  -谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
-你们干什么呢  -跟我散散步啊
- What are you doing? - Wanna walk with me?
-上车啊  -你们干嘛呢
- Get in. - Yeah, what's going on?
好
Yeah.
-我们要去散步  -你们是爱上彼此了吗
- We're gonna walk. - Do you guys love each other?
我明白了
Oh, I get it.
-你们真的爱上彼此了  -别做出格的事哦
- You guys do love each other. - Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
再见了
Okay, goodbye.
好吧  我们走
All right, all right.
那电影真好玩
That was fun.
我都好久没看过电影了
I haven't seen a movie in ages.
是吗
Really?
上次看还是小时候
Not since I was a little kid.
什么
What?
真的
No, I, uh....
我一直很忙  没多少闲暇时间
I'm busy, you know, I don't have a lot of time.
这么忙
You're busy?
我的日程很严格
I have a very strict schedule.
一天天的都计划好了
My days are all planned out.
早上起床
I get up in the morning.
吃早餐  数学课  拉丁语课  吃午饭
Breakfast, math tutor, Latin tutor, lunch.
然后是网球课  舞蹈课  有时都学
Tennis lesson, dance lesson... Sometimes both.
法语课  钢琴课  然后吃晚饭
French tutor, piano lesson, then I eat dinner.
晚饭后跟家人在一起
And after dinner I spend time with my family.
然后读点书
And then I catch up on some reading.
-听上去像是通往成功之路  -可不是嘛
- Sounds like the road to success. - Oh, you bet.
我们要申请好多大学
We're applying to all these colleges.
拉德克里夫  萨拉·劳伦斯  我们想进这些
Um, Radcliffe, Sarah Lawrence. Those are the ones we want.
我们是谁
And who's we?
什么
What?
你说"我们想进这些"
You just said, "The ones that we want."
妈妈和爸爸  我们什么事都一起拿主意
Oh, Mama and Daddy. We decide everything together.
所有事吗
Everything?
当然不是所有了
No, not everything.
就是重要的事
But the important things, yes.
那么其他的事你都能自己拿主意吗
And then everything else, you get to decide all by yourself?
-别那么没礼貌  -抱歉
- Don't be rude. - I'm sorry.
我只是想知道你怎么消遣
Just trying to figure out what you do for fun.
什么意思
What do you mean?
就是...
I mean....
怎么说呢
I don't know.
你刚刚说的那些都是你必须做的  不是吗
I mean all those things are things you have to do, right?
那有什么事是你想做的呢
So, what do you do because you want to?
我都说了
I just told you.
不是吧
I don't know.
真让我没想到
This surprises me.
-为什么  -我只是以为你会是个...
- Why? - I just always figured you were kind of....
是个什么
Kind of what?
就是
Just....
自由的人
Free.
什么
What?
自由
Free.
我挺自由啊
I am free.
你看上去不像
You don't seem like it.
我就是啊
Well, I am.
来  我给你看样东西
Come here, I want to show you something.
-诺亚  你干什么呢  -过来嘛
- Noah, what are you doing? - Just come on.
-你要被轧死的  -因为有很多车吗
- You're gonna get run over. - By all the cars?
我和爸爸以前会来这儿
My Dad and I used to come out here...
躺下来  看着红绿灯变色
...and lay down and watch the lights change.
看灯从绿变红再变黄
Watch them go from green to red to yellow.
你想的话也可以来试试
You could try it, if you wanted to.
-不要  -为什么
- No. - Why not?
因为...我说不清  你起来好吗
Because... I don't know. Will you just get up?
你就是这样  你知道吗
That's your problem, you know that?
你不做你想做的事
You don't do what you want.
好吧
Okay.
要是来车了怎么办
What happens if a car comes?
-那我们就死了  -什么
- We die. - What?
放松就好  有信心
Just relax. Just trust.
你得学会信任
You need to learn how to trust.
好吧
Okay.
画画
Painting.
你之前问我自己喜欢做什么
You asked me what I do for me.
-什么  -我喜欢画画
- What now? - I love to paint.
真的
Yeah?
大多数时候  我脑子总是转个不停
Most of the time, I have all these thoughts bouncing around in my head.
但一拿起画笔  整个世界都安静了
But with a brush in my hand, the world just gets kind of quiet.
别挡路
Get out of the street!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
你笑什么啊
Why are you laughing?
真好玩啊
Oh, that was fun.
你想跟我跳舞吗
Do you wanna dance with me?
好啊
Sure.
现在吗
Now?
就在这儿
Here?
不该在大路中央跳舞的
Not supposed to dance in the middle of the street.
不该在大路中央跳舞啊
Not supposed to dance in the street?
而且也没有音乐伴奏
And we don't have any music.
那我们就唱
Well, we'll make some.
-你唱得好烂  -我知道
- You're a terrible singer. - I know.
但我喜欢这歌
But I like this song.
南方的夏天不在乎年轻的爱情会承受多少考验
Southern summers are indifferent to the trials of young love.
带着一丝戒心和怀疑
Armed with warnings and doubts...
诺亚和艾莉
...Noah and Allie
无疑也成了一对不顾后果
gave a remarkably convincing portrayal of a boy and a girl
踏上了一条漫漫长路的男孩女孩
traveling down a very long road with no regard for the consequences.
他们相爱了  是吗
They fell in love, didn't they?
-是的  -太好了
- Yes, they did. - Good.
我就喜欢这种故事  继续读
I like this kind of story. Go on.
那晚之后
After that night...
艾莉和诺亚天天在一起
...Allie and Noah spent every waking hour together.
很快两人就如胶似漆
And soon they were inseparable.
-诺亚  加油啊  -诺亚才骑不过我呢
- Noah, come on. - Noah cannot beat me there.
-真不错  -你尝尝
- That's really nice. - Try that.
这感觉真不错
That's really nice.
那些湿淋淋的美丽的碎片
Beautiful dripping fragments
那一件件被忽略的事物
The negligent list of one after another
当我偶尔想起他们
As I happen to call them to me
提起他们时
Or drink to them
真正的诗  我们所谓的诗不过是图片
The real poems What we call poems being merely pictures
那些关于静谧的夜晚
The poems of the privacy of the night
和我这种男人的诗
And of men like me
这首诗  羞羞答答地挡着不让人看
This poem, drooping shy and unseen
我总带在身边  每个男人都带在身边
That I always carry And that all men carry
惠特莫写的不赖[《本能的我》]
Not bad for Whitman.
有人来看我们了
Hey, looks like we got a visitor.
抱歉  我没想打扰你们的
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to interrupt.
不用道歉啊  快上来  亲爱的
Well, don't apologize. Come on up here, darling.
我们正需要个不是一身木头味儿的人呢
We could use a little something here besides the smell of lumber.
爸爸  这是艾莉森·汉密尔顿
Dad, this is Allison Hamilton.
艾莉森  见到你很高兴
Allison, I'm glad to meet you.
-艾莉就好  -艾莉
- Allie. - Allie.
见到你也很高兴  卡尔霍恩先生
Pleased to meet you, Mr. Calhoun.
干嘛这么叫  我很老吗
Well, Mr. Calho... What, am I old or something?
叫我弗兰克就好
You can call me Frank.
-过来坐下吧  -好
- Here, come in and have a seat. - Okay.
艾莉  她可真美啊  儿子
So, Allie. Well, she is pretty, son.
-是啊  -比你说的要美多了
- Yes. - She's a lot prettier than you let on.
-是这样吗  -才不是呢
- Oh, is that right? - No, it's not right.
-别相信他  -那是什么
- Don't believe what he says. - What is this you got?
我给你带来点东西
Um, I just... I brought you something.
我看看  让我们瞧瞧
Let me see. Let's have a look.
这是你画的
Did you do this?
真美啊  你快看
Well, that's beautiful. Look at that.
这画画得多好
That's a damn picture there.
我知道该放哪  谢谢
Well, I know just where we can put that, thank you.
那首诗真美
Oh, that was a lovely poem.
是什么
What was it?
-嗯  -惠特莫
- Well... - Whitman.
他小时候口吃得厉害
See, when he was a little kid he used to stutter real bad.
-爸爸  -就是嘛
- Dad... - So... Well, you did.
-这我不知道呢  -天呐  我就是结巴
- I didn't know that. - God. I stammered.
口吃  结巴  有什么区别
Stammered, stutter, what's the difference?
他说话我根本听不懂
Couldn't understand a damn thing he said.
于是我让他大声读诗
So I got him to read me poetry out loud.
起初念得不好  但后来口吃就改掉了
It wasn't very pretty at first, but then his stutter went away.
真是好主意啊  念诗
Well, it's a good idea, that poetry.
是啊
Yeah, I thought so.
受不了你  真受不了你
Unbelievable, unbelievable.
我本人喜欢丁尼生  但他喜欢惠特莫
I'm a Tennyson man myself, but he likes Whitman.
我也不知道为什么
For some reason, I don't know.
想吃早饭吗  要不要吃点早饭
How would you like some breakfast? Would you like some breakfast?
-早饭  -嗯
- Breakfast? - Yeah.
-爸  都10点了  -那又如何
- Dad, it's 10:00. - What's that got to do with it?
想吃薄煎饼还要看时间吗
You can have pancakes any damn time of night you want.
-进来吧  来点早饭吗  -好啊
- Come on, you want some breakfast? - Sure.
那是一段不可能的恋情
It was an improbable romance.
他是个乡下男孩  她是个城里女孩
He was a country boy. She was from the city.
世界都摆在她脚下
She had the world at her feet...
而他却一穷二白
...while he didn't have two dimes to rub together.
诺亚  过来啊
Noah, come on.
看我们啊
Look at us.
我们干什么呢
What are we doing?
你说如果有来世  我会是只鸟吗
Do you think in another life, I could have been a bird?
什么意思啊
What do you mean?
就是轮回转世
Like reincarnation.
不知道
I don't know.
我觉得有可能
I think I could.
说我是只鸟
Say I'm a bird.
不要
No.
-别闹了  -说我是只鸟
- Don't do it. - Say I'm a bird.
快停下  别闹
Stop it. Stop it now.
-才不是呢  -说嘛
- You're not. - Say it!
-你是只鸟  -嗯
- You're a bird. - Yeah.
说你也是只鸟
Now say you're a bird too.
如果你是鸟  那我也是
If you're a bird, I'm a bird.
-来吧  亲爱的  -你要干什么
- Come on, darling. - What are you doing?
别啊  别
Don't. Don't!
好了  数到三
Here we go, on the count of three.
放松点  数到三  好了吗
Real easy, on three, ready?
-好吧  -一
- Okay, okay. - One.
-二  -二
- Two. - Two.
二  三
Two. Three!
不行  我做不到
No! I can't.
快下水
Get in the water!
-快点  抱歉  -快点啊  胆小鬼
- Get in! I'm sorry. - Come on, chicken.
快下水  亲爱的  下水吧
Get in the water, baby. Baby, would you get in?
-快下水啊  -我做不到
- Get in the water. - I can't.
-快点  -快下水
- Go! - Get in the water!
-一  二  -快点  跳吧
- One. Two. - Come on, jump.
三
Three.
踩下去  不对
Keep it down. No, no, no.
-踩到位  -就在这儿
- Get to your good place. - Down here.
然后往前开  别动脚
And move. And keep it.
别动脚
No, don't move it!
我听不懂你在说什么啊
I don't understand what you're talking about.
他们很少达成一致
They didn't agree on much.
事实上  他们意见通常都相左
In fact, they rarely agreed on anything.
他们总在吵架
They fought all the time.
-别踢我  -别推我
- Don't kick me! - Don't push me.
他们每天都跟彼此理论
And they challenged each other every day.
但尽管有那么多分歧
But despite their differences...
他们有一个重要的共同点
...they had one important thing in common.
他们都疯狂地爱着彼此
They were crazy about each other.
我得走了
Okay, I have to go.
-不行  -我真得走了
- No! - Yes, I do.
艾莉
Allie.
爸爸
Daddy.
爸爸...
Oh, Daddy, you...
我没看见你
I didn't see you there.
你吓到我了
You kind of scared me.
你跟那男孩走得很近啊
Becoming friendly with that boy down there.
是啊
Yes.
周日带他来家里
Bring him to the house on Sunday.
我想见见他
I want to meet this young man.
好
Okay.
晚安  爸爸
Good night, Daddy.
晚安
Good night.
天呐
Oh, boy.
儿子就说  "爸爸  我不懂"
Boy goes, "Daddy, I don't understand."
他就说  "理论上说  我们都是百万富翁
He goes, "Well, in theory, we're both millionaires.
但其实呢  我们跟一群妓女住在一起"
But in reality, we live with a bunch of whores."
斯蒂文森主教跟我讲的
Bishop Stevens told me that.
奥利维尔  把酒壶从我丈夫面前拿开
Olivier, please remove the liquor decanter from in front of my husband.
我觉得他已经喝多了
I think he's had too much to drink.
你做什么的  诺亚
So, what do you do, Noah?
我跟芬恩都在贮木场工作
I work at the lumberyard with Fin.
就是加工原木  剥树皮什么的
Mainly milling and receiving logs, and stripping the bark.
-真不错啊  -谢谢
- Well, that's lovely, dear. - Thank you.
如果你不介意我问一句
If you don't mind my asking,
你的工作能挣多少钱
uh, how much do you make at your job?
我挣多少钱
Uh, how much money do I make?
每小时40美分
About 40 cents an hour.
是不多  但我也用不着多少
Yeah, it's not much, but I don't need a lot.
而且我大都存下来了
And I save most of it.
我们吃吧
Let's eat. Shall we?
嗯  这看上去好美味
Yes! Oh, it looks delicious.
诺亚  你最近总跟艾莉在一起啊
So, Noah, you and Allie have been spending a lot of time together.
你俩肯定很喜欢对方
You must be very fond of each other.
你们挺认真的了  是吗
It's getting pretty serious, huh?
是的
Yes, ma'am.
夏天就要结束了  你打算怎么办
Well, summer's almost gone. What will you do?
查尔斯顿也就几小时的路嘛
You know, Charleston's only a couple of hours away.
但艾莉要去萨拉·劳伦斯学院了啊
But Allie's going to Sarah Lawrence.
她没告诉你吗
Didn't she tell you?
没有呢
No, she didn't tell me that.
我刚刚收到录取信  我打算告诉你的
I just got the letter. I was gonna tell you.
没事
It's okay.
萨莉·劳伦斯在纽约
And Sarah Lawrence is in New York.
这我不知道呢
I didn't know that.
安  这么闷的话题别在饭桌上说了
Anne, this conversation's too stuffy for the dinner table.
让孩子们好好玩
Let the children have fun
别非得搞得像宗教审判似的
without bringing in the Spanish Inquisition.
我这就不说了
My lips are buttoned, right now.
我还知道一个笑话
I do know another joke
是关于修女和主教的
about the nun and the full standing bishop.
你再讲笑话我就要离席了
I'm leaving the table if you tell another joke.
我真这么做了
I'm gonna do it.
-嗯  -好啊
- Yeah. - Yeah.
以她的身份  这孩子太过活跃了
That child's got too much spirit for a girl of her circumstance.
只是夏日恋情而已
No, it's just summer love.
我看是麻烦
Trouble is what it is.
是艾莉吗
Is that Allie out there?
想去别的地方吗
Do you wanna go somewhere?
好啊
Okay.
等在这儿
Wait here.
艾莉
Allie!
过来
Come on.
好了  迈一大步
All right, big step.
一大步  别...
Big step. No, don't...
好了  待这儿
All right, just stay there.
别睁眼
Don't open your eyes.
好了
Okay.
温莎种植园
The Windsor Plantation.
1772年建造的
It was built in 1772.
据说弗兰西斯·马里昂
Rumor has it that Francis Marion...
独立战争时期军人
就是在这台阶上向他妻子求婚的
...proposed to his wife right here under these, uh... These steps.
小心
Watch out.
小心  台阶是坏掉的  看那儿
You be careful, these are broken. Look at that.
这里好大啊
This place is gigantic.
是啊  好大一堆破烂
Yeah, a gigantic piece of crap.
就是啊
It is.
但我将来要把它买下来  修葺好
But I'm gonna buy it one day and I'm gonna fix it up.
就需要装个新地板
All it needs is a new floor.
和新墙壁  新屋顶
And new walls and roof.
-这就够了吗  -还有管道  电线
- Is that all? - And plumbing and electric.
-家具  -对  家具
- And furniture. - Yes, some furniture.
但供水没问题
But it's right on the water.
而且那边还有个大谷仓
And there's a big old barn up there,
我可以改造成工作间
I could turn that into my workshop.
那我呢
Well, what about me?
我就没有发言权了吗
Now, don't I get any say in this?
你想要发言权吗
You want a say in this?
想啊
Yes, I would.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我要房子刷成白的
I want a white house...
挂蓝色百叶窗
...with blue shutters.
还要一间河景房间  让我画画
And a room overlooking the river so I could paint.
-还有别的吗  -嗯
- Anything else? - Yes.
我要一个环绕整栋房子的门廊
I want a big old porch that wraps around the entire house.
我们就能喝茶
We can drink tea...
一起看日落
...and watch the sun go down.
-好  -你保证
- Okay. - You promise?
嗯  我保证
Mm- hm, I promise.
很好
Good.
-你去哪  -这里
- Where are you going? - In here.
你这样我都没法弹《筷子》了
I can't play "Chopsticks" if you're doing that.
实为肖邦E小调前奏曲OP.28
天呐
Oh, God.
跟我做爱吧
Oh, make love to me.
-诺亚  -嗯
- Noah. Um.... - Yeah?
我知道我说我想跟你做爱
I know I said that I wanted you to make love to me...
-但我觉得...  -怎么了
- ...but I think you... - Yeah?
你得跟我说说话
You're gonna have to talk me through this.
-好吧  你没事吧  -嗯
- Right. You all right? - Yeah.
-弄疼你了吗  -没有
- Did I hurt you? - No, no.
我就是脑子里好乱
I'm just... I'm just having a lot of thoughts.
我就是脑子里...
I'm just... I'm just having a lot of...
算了  没事
Oh, never mind.
你在想什么啊  你现在在想什么
Like, what are you thinking? What are you thinking right now?
就是此时此刻
You know, right this second?
你带我来的时候就知道我们会这样吗
Did you know that this was gonna happen when you brought me here?
-不啊  -不吗
- No. - No?
-嗯  -你没想过吗
- No. - No, you didn't think about it?
-我当然想过了  -是吗
- Of course I thought about it. - You did?
你怎么想的
Well, what did you think?
我话太多了  是吗
Oh, I'm talking too much, aren't l?
好了  我不说了
Okay, okay, I'm just gonna shut up.
嘴巴紧闭
Mum's the word.
好了
Okay.
-你没事吧  -嗯
- You all right? - Yeah.
好吧
All right.
我就是不懂你怎么会这么沉默
I just don't understand how come you're so quiet.
你什么想法都没有吗
You don't have one thought?
我都要疯了
I'm going crazy over here...
但你好像没事人似的
...but, no, with you, everything's fine.
你什么都不在乎吗
You don't have a care in the world?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我好希望这一切很完美
I wanted this to be so perfect...
结果我却说个不停
...and now I can't shut up.
我爱你
I love you.
你知道吧
Did you know that?
我也爱你
I love you too.
你不想做的话不要勉强自己
You don't have to do this if you don't want to.
不  我想的  真的
No, no, I want to, I do.
诺亚
Noah!
干什么  芬恩  快出去
What? Fin, get out of here!
抱歉  但艾莉的父母都要疯了
Look, I'm sorry, but Allie's parents are going crazy.
他们把镇上的警察都叫出来找她了
They got every cop in town out looking for her.
-你居然派警察找我  -没错
- You sent the police for me? - Yes.
都凌晨2点了  所以我们叫警察了
It is 2 in the morning. We sent the police.
幸好你没事  你去哪了
Thank God you're all right. Where you been?
汉密尔顿先生  这是我的错
Mr. Hamilton, all this is my fault.
能让我们单独待会儿吗
Would you give us a moment, please?
我想跟我女儿谈谈
I'd like to talk to my daughter.
跟你一个人谈
Alone, young lady.
多谢了  副队
Thanks for everything, lieutenant.
不客气  约翰
You bet, John, anytime.
快回家吧  都这么晚了
You go straight home now, it's late.
先生  这真的不怪她
Sir, it's really not her fault.
是我忘记时间了
I lost track of time.
坐吧
Sit down.
对不起  爸爸
I'm sorry, Daddy.
就这一句吗
"I'm sorry, Daddy"?
你以为你跟你爸装装可怜就能蒙混过去吗
Think you can bat your eyelashes at your father and get away with it?
休想  这次我们得立点规矩了
No. This time there's going to start being some rules around here.
什么规矩
Like what?
你父亲如果不肯执行  那就我来
If your father won't enforce them, I will.
-什么规矩  妈妈  -你不能再见诺亚了
- Like what, Mother? - You are gonna stop seeing Noah.
她跟那小子一直在外面待到凌晨2点
She is out fooling around with that boy till 2:00 in the morning.
不能再这么下去了
It has got to stop.
我花了17年养女儿  给了她一切
I didn't spend 17 years of my life raising a daughter...
我绝不允许她为了一段夏日恋情
...and giving her everything so she could throw it away...
-就抛弃一切  -爸爸  说句公道话啊
- ...on a summer romance. - Daddy, come on!
这么下去  她不是伤透心  就是怀孕
She will wind up with her heart broken or pregnant.
-安  别这样  -他人是不错
- Anne, please. - Now, he is a nice boy.
他人是不错  但是...
He's a nice boy, but he's...
他怎么了
He's what?
-他怎么了  说啊  -他是下等人
- He's what? Tell me. - He is trash, trash, trash.
配不上你
Not for you.
-下等人  -他是个工人  木工
- Trash? - He's a laborer. He's a woodworker.
-那又如何  -你想怎么样
- So what? - What are you gonna do?
搬到这儿来
Are you gonna move down here,
住在他父亲家  跟他生几个孩子吗
live in his father's house and pop out a few kids?
我觉得挺好啊
Yeah, well, I wouldn't mind.
别碰我
Don't touch me!
你不许再见他了  就这么定了
You are not to see him anymore, and that's final.
-不行  -没商量
- No, it's not final. - Yes, it is.
不行
No, it's not final!
你休想告诉我我该爱谁
You're not gonna tell me who I'm gonna love.
-爱  -对  爸爸  我爱他
- Love? - Yes, Daddy, I love him.
我爱他
I love him.
他不合适你  孩子
He's not suitable for you, baby.
我爱他
I love him.
你才17岁  你才不懂什么叫爱呢
You are 17 years old, you don't know anything about love.
你就懂吗
Oh, and you do?
你看爸爸的眼神根本不像我看诺亚那样
You don't look at Daddy the way I look at Noah.
你不摸他  不笑
You don't touch or laugh.
你们不跟他打闹  你才不懂什么叫爱呢
You don't play. You don't know anything about love.
诺亚
Noah?
你要走了吗
You leaving?
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
真不知道该说什么  太丢人了
I don't even know what to say. I'm humiliated.
-没事的  -有事
- It's all right. - No, it's not.
-没事  -有事的
- Yeah. - No, it's not.
-我要走了  -我不想你走
- I'm gonna go. - No, I don't want you to go.
我得考虑一下
I gotta think about some stuff.
你要考虑什么啊
What do you gotta think about, huh?
跟我说话啊
Come here and talk to me.
-跟我说话  -说什么  你要...
- Talk to me! - About what? You want...
你要走了
You're going away!
你要离开了
You're leaving.
而我还得留在这儿
And I'm staying here.
我很高兴你要去求学了
And I'm so happy that you're doing that...
但你会忙得不可开交
...but you're gonna have a million things to do.
-不  -你有大好的人生
- No. - You got so much ahead of you.
-别这么说  -就是这样啊
- Don't talk like that. - It's true.
我不会有什么好东西  奢侈的东西
I'm not gonna have nice things, fancy things.
我不...
It doesn't...
我没那个命  对我来说是不可能的
It's never gonna happen for me. It's not in the cards for me.
-我不用去上学的  -你当然得去
- I don't have to go to school, okay? - Yes, you do.
-我可以留下  -不行
- I can stay here. - No.
你瞧  我说的就是这个
You see, that's exactly what I'm talking about.
那你就跟我一起来啊
Then you can come with me.
-去纽约  -对
- To New York? - Yes.
我去纽约干什么啊
What am I gonna do in New York?
跟我在一起
Be with me?
嗯
Yeah.
我说不好
I don't know.
我们不非得今晚上都想明白了
We don't gotta figure all this out tonight, you know?
等夏天结束的时候再考虑吧
We'll finish out the summer and we'll see what happens.
你是说你想跟我分手吗
You saying you want to break it off?
我只是说回头再看看吧
What I'm saying, we see how it goes later on.
你是要跟我分手吗
Are you breaking up with me?
我觉得这样下去行不通的
I don't see how it's gonna work.
我懂了
I see.
别这样
Please don't do this.
你不是真心的
You don't mean it.
好吧  既然你要分手
Oh, hell, well, if you're gonna do it,
何必等到夏天结束
why wait until the summer ends, huh?
现在就分吧
Why don't you just do it right now?
来啊
Come on.
-来啊  -你干什么啊
- Come on. - What are you doing?
分手啊
Do it! Do it!
跟我分手啊
Do it right now.
快点
Do it!
够了
Stop it!
还是我来吧  我跟你完了
You know what? I'm gonna do it. It's over.
好吗  我跟你完了
Okay? It's over.
-过来  -别碰我
- Come here. - Don't touch me.
我恨你  我恨你
I hate you, I hate you.
我走了
I'm gonna go.
走啊  你赶快走啊  滚蛋
Why don't you? Why don't you just go? Get out.
滚啊  滚
Leave! Go! Go!
等等  我们不是真要分手吧
No, no, just wait a minute. We're not really breaking up, are we?
别这样  我们只是吵个架而已
Come on. This is just a fight we're having.
明天又会像没事一样了  对吗
And tomorrow it'll be like it never happened, right?
-走了  -是啊
- Gone? - Gone.
她一定伤心死了
Well, she must have been devastated.
是啊
She was.
他只是想为她着想
He was only trying to do the right thing.
是啊
Yeah.
但其实他真应该
But what he really should have done
让她父母滚蛋去
is just told those parents to go to hell.
让他们哪凉快哪玩去
Just stick it where the sun don't shine.
是啊  或许是该如此
Yeah, you're right, probably should've.
第二天
The next day...
艾莉醒过来  却发现她的世界已天翻地覆
...Allie woke up to find her world completely changed.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我们要回家了
We're going home.
现在就走吗
We're going now?
我们还要再待一周的
No, we're not supposed to be leaving for another week.
去换衣服然后来吃早餐  亲爱的
Get dressed and then come and have some breakfast, dear.
薇拉会给你收拾东西
Willa will pack your things.
我很乐意给你收拾东西  艾莉小姐
I'd be happy to pack your things, Miss Allie.
我不要你给我收拾东西
I don't want you to pack my things.
别动我的东西  我不要走
I don't want you to touch my stuff. I'm not going.
-你要走  -不  我不走
- Yes, you are. - No, I'm not.
-艾莉  你一定要走  -不要
- Yes, Allie, you are. - No, I'm not.
艾莉  不管你想不想  都得跟我们走
Allie, you are going whether you like it or not.
哪怕要让艾伦扛着你
Now, even if Aaron has to throw you over his shoulder...
一路回家去  你也要走
and drag you the whole way, you're going.
借过
Excuse me.
芬恩
Fin!
诺亚呢
Where's Noah?
他去送木材了
He's out delivering a load.
-怎么了  -我要走了
- What's going on? - I'm leaving town.
-走了  -是
- Leaving? - Yeah.
-什么时候  -现在  就今天
- When? - Now. Right now. Like today.
你替我给诺亚带个话好吗
Look, I need you to tell Noah something, okay?
告诉他我爱他
I need you to tell him that I love him.
告诉他我很抱歉
Tell him that I'm sorry for everything, okay?
我一整夜都陪着他  艾莉
Look, I was up all night with him, Allie.
我从没见过他那么难过
I've never seen him so low.
你俩结束了  别弄得大家更难过了
It's over. Don't make it any harder than it already is.
不是的  我们没结束
No! No, it's not over.
芬恩  我们昨晚是吵了一架
Fin, we had a fight last night.
说了一些过分的话  但我们没结束
We said some things we didn't mean, but it's not over.
-就是结束了  -没有
- lt is over. - No.
别纠缠了  放手吧
Leave it alone. Let it go.
我就来  妈妈  我就来
I'm coming. Mama, I'm coming!
-他懂的  -但是...
- Look, he understands. - But...
虽然很难接受  但他真的理解你的
It's hard, but he really does.
夏季结束了  该回家了
Summer's over and it's time to go home.
如果他想跟你说话  就会写信的  否则...
If he wants to talk to you, he'll write. If not?
好吧
Okay.
那你能...
Okay, can you just...?
你能告诉他我爱他吗
Can you just tell him that I love him, then?
行吗
Can you do that?
我会转告的
I'll tell him.
再见  芬恩
Bye, Fin.
她走了
She's gone.
夏季恋情的开始各式各样
Summer romances begin for all kinds of reasons.
但说到底
But when all is said and done...
他们有一个共同点
...they have one thing in common:
他们都是流星
They are shooting stars.
是天空中灿烂辉煌的一瞬
A spectacular moment of light in the heavens.
是稍纵即逝的永恒
A fleeting glimpse of eternity.
转眼之间  便消逝了
And in a flash, they're gone.
诺亚十分绝望
Noah was desperate.
他写信告诉艾莉他很抱歉
He wrote to Allie that he was sorry
是他太傻  不该跟她分手
and stupid for breaking up with her.
他写信说他还爱着她
He wrote to tell her that he still loved her,
想再见到她
and he wanted to see her.
如果她肯回信
And that if she would write back,
他愿去天涯海角找到她
he would come to wherever she was.
卡尔霍恩  致艾莉·汉密尔顿小姐
他每天都写一封信  写了一年  365封信
He wrote one letter a day for a year, 365 letters.
但都石沉大海
But they all went unanswered.
弗莱德  没我的信吗
Hey, Fred! Nothing?
-抱歉  -好吧  谢啦
- Sorry. - All right, thank you.
最终  一年的杳无音信
Finally, after a year of silence...
让他决定放下这一切  开始新的生活
...he decided to put it all behind him and start a new life.
于是他写了一封道别信
So he wrote a farewell letter...
跟芬恩一起收拾行李
...and he and Fin packed their bags...
去了亚特兰大
...and headed for Atlanta.
诺亚  诺亚
Noah! Noah!
诺亚
Noah!
来啊  听听这个
Come on, listen to this!
美国和日本帝国之间
A state of war has existed...
已处于战争状态
...between the United States and the....
...美国的宪法
...The Constitution of the United States...
抵御一切国外和国内的敌人
...against all enemies, foreign and domestic.
诺亚和芬恩一起入伍了
Noah and Fin enlisted together.
在北非沙漠里
And after two years of chasing
跟隆美尔周旋了两年
Rommel through the North African desert...
随后被调派去巴顿在欧洲的第三军团
...they were deployed to Patton's Third Army in Europe.
芬恩
Fin!
我是否自相矛盾呢
Do I contradict myself?
草叶集
好吧  我就是自相矛盾
Very well, then, I contradict myself...
艾莉当时在上大三
Allie was in her third year of college...
她志愿成为了护士助手
...when she volunteered as a nurse's aid.
对她而言  病房里的那些
To her, the broken men with shattered bodies...
遍体鳞伤的男人都是诺亚
...who filled the ward were all Noah.
或是曾跟他一起在丛林
Or someone who fought beside him in the jungle...
或雪域奋战的人
...or a frozen snow-swept road.
我来把你抬起来
I'm gonna lift you up.
准备好了吗
Ready?
好了
There we go.
我要把这条腿抬过来
Now, I'm gonna bring this leg over.
放在脚凳上
Set it on the stool.
-还好吗  -嗯
- You okay? - Yeah.
小姐  能问个问题吗
Miss, can I ask you a question?
我注意到你没有戴婚戒
I noticed that you aren't wearing a ring.
我想问你是否愿意跟我出去
And I was wondering if I could take you out.
-什么  -去约会
- Excuse me? - On a date.
在你拒绝我之前
Now, before you go and say no...
我想告诉你我舞跳得很好
...I'll have you know that I am an excellent dancer.
而且我绝对不怀好意
And my intentions are completely dishonorable.
好了  大情圣  来吧
Okay, okay, Casanova, come on.
先把身体养好了
Let's just get you better,
再考虑约会的事  好吗
and then we'll talk about a date, okay?
快看看他啊
Would you get a load of him?
天呐  他真帅
Oh, my gosh, he is dreamy.
他在这儿干什么
What is he doing here?
他在盯着你看呢
He's staring at you.
小姐
Oh, miss?
我身体养好了
I'm all better.
愿跟我约会吗
Now, how's about that date?
艾莉惊讶于自己是多快就爱上了朗·哈蒙德
Allie was surprised how quickly she fell in love with Lon Hammond.
他帅气  聪明
He was handsome, smart...
风趣  世故  有魅力
...funny, sophisticated and charming.
他也来自南方的世家
He also came from old Southern money...
而且富得流油
...and was fabulously wealthy.
怎么回事
Oh, what's happening?
-你们去哪  -他们要去哪
- Where are you going? - Where they going?
-回见了  亲爱的  -瞧啊
- See you later, sweetheart. - Look at that.
艾莉  我一直在考虑我们不该结婚的理由
Allie, I've been thinking a lot about why we shouldn't get married.
好吧  我们为什么不该结婚
Okay, I give up, why shouldn't we get married?
问题就在这儿  我起初想不到
That's the thing, I couldn't think of anything at first.
然后突然就想起来了  你父母
And then, it just dawned on me. Your parents.
-我父母  -没错
- My parents? - Absolutely.
你父母  多谢了啊
Your old mom and dad. Thank you for that.
-老妈啊  -问题是  他们很喜欢我
- Mom? - You see, the problem is that they love me.
-我正是他们心中的...  -是吗
- I'm exactly the type of man... - They do?
-如意女婿  -真的啊
- ...they want you to end up with. - Really?
我有钱  来自南方  工作也不错
You know, I'm wealthy, I'm from the South, I got a decent job.
我舞跳得棒  人也机灵
You know, I'm an incredible dancer, I'm a really smart guy.
长得还帅
I look great.
-那问题在哪里啊  -我认为...
- So, what's the problem, huh? - I like to think...
是这样  如果你嫁给我
Now just this. If you marry me...
听好了
Now listen close.
如果你嫁给我
If you marry me...
那么你这辈子叛逆他们的战役就失败了
...then you will have lost a lifelong battle of defiance against them.
-老天啊  这可怎么办  -我不知道
- My goodness. What are we gonna do? - I do not know.
乐队  感觉怎么样
Hey, band, you feeling all right?
伙计  感觉不错呢
Hey, man, we're feeling all right.
你们来
You say it!
艾莉  我觉得...你必须嫁给我
See, Allie, I think... Damn it, I think you have to marry me.
-我觉得你一定得嫁给我  -是吗
- I think you need to marry me. - I do?
-是的  -为什么
- Yes, you do. - I do, why?
因为  如果你嫁给我  你父母就会知道
Because if you do, your parents will always know...
你因为没能让他们失望
...the unhappiness that you feel
而有多么的郁闷
for not being able to disappoint them.
我觉得你可能忘记了一个小小的细节
I think you may have overlooked one minor detail.
什么啊
And what's that?
你得先得到他们的允许
Well, you see, you have to get their permission first.
而我觉得你可能高估了他们对你的喜爱
And I think you may have overestimated their affection for you.
是吗
Is that right?
我觉得不会
Oh, I don't think so.
-为什么  -因为我已经问过了
- And why not? - Oh, because I asked them already...
他们同意了
...and they said yes.
什么
What?
还有一件事
One more thing.
我爱你
I love you.
能嫁给我吗  艾莉
Will you marry me, Allie?
我知道我常打诨  但我为你疯狂
I know I kid around a lot, but I'm crazy about you.
嫁给我吧  让我成为世上最幸福的男人
Marry me? Make me the happiest man in the world?
好啊  好
Yes. Yes, yes!
-等等我  -你去哪
- Just hold tight. - Where are you going?
天呐  妈妈
Oh, my. Mama.
让乐队停下
Okay, stop the band.
打扰下  我想要大家知道
Excuse me. I'd like everyone here to know...
那位小姐要跟我结婚了
...that this young lady and I are getting married.
她的答应确实是出自真心  但却不明白
She agreed with all her heart, but couldn't understand...
为什么她说"好"的那一刻
...why at the very moment she said yes...
脑中却浮现出诺亚的脸
...Noah's face came to her mind.
诺亚
Hey, Noah, yeah!
见到你太好了  让我瞧瞧你
Oh, good to see you. Let me see you.
你哪里有伤吗
You bleeding anywhere? No?
一切都好吗  -嗯
- Everything good? - Yeah.
我真爱你
Oh, I love you.
来吧  给你看样东西  来吧
Come on, there's something I gotta show you. Come on.
怎么回事  怎么了
What's going on? What is this?
给
Here.
我卖了房子
I sold the house.
-你卖了房子  -对
- You sold the house? - Yup.
月底就得搬走了
Gotta be out by the end of the month.
这个  加上你的军饷
Between that and your GI Bill,
你应该就能买下了
you ought to be able to get it now.
-买什么  -你想要的那栋房子
- Get what? - Your dream house.
-温莎种植园  -爸爸
- The Windsor Plantation. - Dad...
别来这套  什么都别说
Don't "dad" me, I don't wanna hear about it.
我已经跟银行商量过了  他们会给你贷款
I already talked to the bank, they're gonna give you the loan.
-我不能让你卖房子啊  -已经卖了
- Well, I can't let you sell your house. - It's done.
这是好事  去做吧
It's a good thing. You should do it.
等等  你卖了房子  你去哪住啊
Wait a second. You sell the house, where are you gonna live?
跟你住啊  傻子  你以为呢
With you, dummy, what do you think?
总得有人帮你修葺啊
Somebody's gotta help you fix it up.
诺亚看了一眼那栋房子
Noah took a look at the house...
却只看到了
...but only saw one thing:
艾莉
Allie.
于是他决定实现自己人生的梦想
He decided right there to fulfill his lifelong dream.
他要从零开始重建老房子
He would rebuild the old house from the ground up.
诺亚去查尔斯顿审批建筑计划时
And when Noah went to Charleston to get the building plans approved
命运给了他甜蜜的一击
fate stepped in and dealt him a sweet card.
停车  停下车
Stop the bus! Stop the bus.
抱歉  没到站不能停车
Sorry, I can't stop the bus until I get to the depot.
不不  求你马上停车吧
No, please stop the bus now. Please.
你听的懂英语吧
Do you understand English, pal?
不到站不能停车  坐下吧
No one gets off till we get to the depot. Now sit down.
天呐
God.
看着点  你个混球
Watch it, screwball!
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
他就在那边
He's right over there.
亲爱的  你好
Baby, hello.
小心
Hold it.
那天见到艾莉后
After seeing Allie that day...
诺亚内心有什么破碎了
...something inside Noah snapped.
他脑子里钻进了一个念头
He got the notion into his head...
如果他能修好他们那晚上去的老房子
that if he restored the old house where they had come that night
艾莉就终会回到他身边
...Allie would find a way to come back to him.
有人称之为心甘情愿
Some called it a labor of love.
也有人会有别的看法
Others called it something else.
但实际上  诺亚是有点疯了
But in fact, Noah had gone a little mad.
-打扰  -那么...
- Excuse me. - Would...
该吃饭了
It's time to eat.
今天午餐在日光室
Lunch will be served in the Sun Room today.
瓜很好吃  我尝了一口
The melon is good. I had a bite.
他们后来还再见到彼此了吗
Did they ever see each other again?
诺亚和艾莉
Noah and Allie?
你总不想我提前剧透吧
Now you don't want me to spoil the end of the story...
我还没讲到精彩的部分呢
...before I get to the good part, do you?
上次说到哪了
Where did I leave off?
我将无欲无求
I shall not want.
11月  诺亚的父亲去世了
When Noah's father died in November...
房子成了他的唯一
...the house was all he had.
他引领我走向...
He leadeth me down....
终于  诺亚修好了房子
In time, Noah finished the house.
笑笑  来
Okay, smile. Here we go.
他好好看了一眼他的作品
He took a good look at what he had accomplished...
连续10天喝得烂醉
...got rip-roaring drunk for 10 days...
认真考虑要不要把它烧了
...thought seriously about setting it on fire...
最终决定挂牌出售
...then finally put the house up for sale.
我愿给你这么多
I'm prepared to offer you this much.
有不少感兴趣的买家
He had a number of interested buyers...
但他总能找到不卖的理由
...but he always found a reason not to sell it to them.
不行
No.
不是出价太低
Either their bids were too low...
如果买家同意了他的要价
...or if they met his asking price,
他又会觉得还不够
he felt it was worth a lot more.
价格真高  但我要了
It's a lot of money, but I'll take it.
五万
Fifty thousand dollars.
-比我的要价还高  -没错
- That's more than my asking price. - That's right.
可是个占便宜的买卖
It's a great deal more.
他跟出价超过他要价五千美元的人说
He told the man that offered him $5000 over his price...
精神正常的人是绝不会那么做的
...that no one in his right mind would do that...
而他绝不会允许一个疯子住在这栋房子里
...and he wouldn't have a lunatic living in his house.
每天早上
He worked out his frustration
他在小湾排解忧思
with life on the creek every morning.
到了晚上  能帮他缓解寂寞的
And in the evenings, to temper the sting of loneliness...
是玛莎·肖
...there was Martha Shaw.
玛莎的丈夫死于战争  她住在隔壁奎尔山镇
Martha was a war widow who lived in Quail Ridge, a town away.
你明天想出去吗
So you wanna go out tomorrow?
我得工作
I gotta work.
如果你想  我们可以去河边
Well, we could go down to the river if you want to.
下周吧
Next week, sometime.
或许可以出去兜兜风
Maybe take a drive somewhere?
不了
No.
只是问问而已
Well, I'm just asking you.
你想要什么  诺亚
What do you want, Noah?
什么意思
What do you mean, what do I want?
从我这儿
From me.
有时候你跟我说话  却根本没在看我
Sometimes when you talk to me, you don't even see me.
男人如果看着一个女人却想着别人
Look, a woman knows when a man looks into her eyes
女人是知道的
and sees someone else.
我也想给你一切你想要的东西
Now, you know I want to give you all the things that you want.
你知道吧
Right?
但我做不到
But I can't.
因为那已经没了
Because they're gone.
已经破碎了
They're broken.
好吗
All right?
头纱会太夸张吗
Is the veil too much?
开什么玩笑  你简直太美了
Are you kidding? You look perfect!
你真是最美的新娘
You're the most beautiful bride.
-你可真美  -亲爱的
- You look gorgeous, honey. - Thank you.
等朗看到你穿这身  一定要疯了
Wait until Lon sees you in this dress, he's gonna go crazy.
他的眼睛要黏在你身上了
He won't be able to take his eyes off you.
手也是
Or his hands.
你真坏
Oh, you are bad!
你看到今早的报纸了吗
Have you seen this morning's paper?
《日报》说你会成为
The Daily Journal says that you are going to be...
这一季的社交亮点
...the social highlight of the season.
这一季
Of the season?
这将是小镇空前的盛会
This is a celebration the likes of which this town's never seen!
她可不是一般的计划家  是不是
She doesn't plan, she plots, doesn't she?
妈妈  看啊  州长也要来
Mama, look, the governor's coming.
那最好  我看
He better. Let me see.
溪镇老房完成翻修
天呐
Oh, boy.
-萨凡纳  怎么样了  -82了
- All right, Savannah, where are we at? - We're 82 now.
-孟菲斯呢  -89了
- Memphis, where are we at? - We're 89 now.
-89  很好从85涨上来的  -先生
- Eighty-nine, great, up from 85. Yes? - Sir?
有人来看你
You have a visitor.
你好啊  亲爱的  我不知道你要来
Well, hello. Baby, I didn't know you were coming.
对不起  我该打个电话的
I'm so sorry, I should have called.
别傻了  打什么电话  你随时能来
Baby, what are you talking about? You don't have to call.
-伙计们  能让我们单独待会儿吗  -好的
- Guys, could you give us a minute? - All right.
好的  先生  艾莉小姐
Yes, sir. Miss Allie.
女士  你好
Ma'am.
怎么了
So, what's up?
我现在不画画了
I don't paint anymore.
我以前总画画的
I used to paint all the time.
我可喜欢画画了
I really loved it.
-我不知道呢  -是啊
- I didn't know that. - Yeah.
那就画呗
So paint.
我会的  我...
I will. You know...
我要开始画画了
...I'm gonna start.
好啊
Great.
你没事吧
Is everything okay?
我得离开一下
I need to get away.
好吧
Okay.
有些事  我要去处理
I need to take care of a few things.
清理一下思绪
I need to clear my head.
好吧  我需要担心吗
Okay, should I be worried?
-不  应该不用  -那我放心点了
- No, I don't think so. - Oh, that's reassuring.
你真的没事吗
Listen, are you all right?
-嗯  -好  那去吧
- Yeah. - Okay, then go.
慢慢来  做完你要做的事
Take your time, do whatever you need to do.
紧张是正常的
It's okay to be nervous.
婚礼前有点退缩是很常见的
It's normal to get cold feet before your wedding.
不  我没有退缩
No, no second thoughts.
我爱你
I love you.
我几天就从溪镇回来  好吗
I'm gonna be back from Seabrook in a couple of days, okay?
-溪镇  -对  溪镇
- Seabrook? - Yeah, Seabrook.
溪镇
你好啊
Hello.
我在报纸上看到了你的照片
I saw your picture in the paper.
就是你跟房子的合照
The one with you and the house.
我就是想过来看看你
And I just wanted to come and see if you were okay.
我倒不是顺道什么的  就是...
I mean, I wasn't in the neighborhood or anything. I just....
你挺好的吗
So are you okay?
那好
Okay, good.
我真蠢  我不该来的
I'm a stupid woman, I shouldn't have come.
你要进来吗
You want to come in?
好吧
Okay.
这故事真不错
This is a good story.
你喜欢我很高兴
I'm glad you like it.
我好像听过
I think I've heard it before.
是啊
Yes.
不止一次吗
Perhaps more than once?
医生要见你
Doctor needs to see you.
-我  现在吗  -不  是他
- Me? Now? - No, him.
但他还没读完故事呢
But he hasn't finished reading the story.
等跟医生完事了  我会再给你读的
I'll read some more when I'm through with the doctor.
不会要很久的
It shouldn't take too long.
-好吧  -你可别乱跑
- All right. - Don't you go away.
我就回来
I'll be right back.
你等的时候  要不要弹会儿钢琴
While you waiting, maybe you'd like to play the piano for a few minutes.
你喜欢弹钢琴的
You do like that.
是吗
I do?
-我不知道什么曲子  -你识谱
- I don't know any tunes. - You can read music.
真的
No kidding?
你是哪位
Who are you?
巴恩维尔医生  新来的一位主治医生
I'm Dr. Barnwell, one of the new attending physicians.
我们还没正式见过  所以我想亲自给你做检查
We haven't met, so I thought I'd examine you myself.
那么这里写着
Okay, so I see here
过去18个月里你两次心脏病发
that you've had two heart attacks over the last 18 months.
嗯  都是轻度的  有一次好像是心绞痛
Yeah, minor ones, I think one was angina.
-有并发症吗  -没有  感觉很棒
- Okay, any complications? - Nope, feel fine.
好吧  深呼吸
Okay, deep breath for me.
再来一次
Okay, one more time.
And deep breath.
再来
And one more.
很棒  你还在服药吗
Terrific, terrific. You still taking your medication?
-每天两次  -很好
- Every day, twice a day. - Good, good, good.
把衣服穿好吧
Okay, you can put your shirt on.
你给汉密尔顿女士读书  是吗
So I understand that you read to Miss Hamilton.
是的  帮她恢复记忆
Yeah, to help her remember.
你觉得这没用吗
You don't think it'll help?
嗯  我觉得没用
No, I don't.
她会回忆起来  医生
She remembers, doc.
我给她读书  她就会想起来
I read to her and she remembers.
并不总会  但有时候会
Not always, but she remembers.
老年痴呆是个不可逆的过程
But senile dementia is irreversible.
是一种衰退
It's degenerative.
到了一定程度  病人就不会再回忆起来了
After a certain point, its victims don't come back.
是啊  他们也总这么跟我说
Yeah, that's what they keep telling me.
我只是不希望你太抱希望
I just don't want you to get your hopes up.
谢了  医生  但常言道
Well, thanks, doc, but you know what they say.
科学有界  上帝无边
Science goes only so far and then comes God.
上帝无边
Then comes God.
该死  他们忘记给她翻谱了
Damn, they forgot to turn the page for her.
完事了吗
You through with me?
看来是翻了
I guess they flipped that page.
不  她是在凭记忆弹
No, that she's playing by memory.
他叫小朗·哈蒙德
His name is Lon Hammond, Jr.
哈蒙德  哈蒙德棉花那个吗
Hammond? As in Hammond Cotton?
就是那个
As in Hammond Cotton.
那你父母一定爱死他了
Well, your parents must love him.
他真的是个好人  诺亚  你会喜欢他的
He's a really good man, Noah. You'd really like him.
你爱他吗
You love him?
是的  我很爱他
Yeah, I do. I love him very much.
那就这样了
Well, that's that.
你嫁给朗  我们做朋友
You marry Lon and we can be friends.
对吧
Right?
嗯
Right.
你饿了吗
Are you hungry?
要留下吃晚饭吗
Do you want to stay for dinner?
我得警告你  我一喝就醉
I have to warn you, I'm a cheap drunk.
再喝几瓶
A couple more of these and
你就得把我扛出去了
you're gonna be carrying me right out of here.
那你慢慢来
Well, go slow then,
我就不用占你便宜了
I don't want to have to take advantage of you.
你不敢  我可是已婚妇女
You wouldn't dare. I'm a married woman.
还没结婚呢
Not yet.
怎么了
What?
干嘛那么看着我
Why are you looking at me like that?
就是想起一些事
Just memories.
这个房间
This room.
这儿就是我们...
This... Is this where...?
就是这里吗
This is the room?
-我吃饱了  -我也是
- I'm full. - Me too.
你的手指抚弄得我好想睡去
O how your fingers drowse me!
惠特曼《再见!》
你的气息落在我周身犹如甘露
Your breath falls around me like dew
你的脉搏宁静了我的耳膜
Your pulse lulls the tympans of my ears
好像从头到脚都沉浸了
I feel immerged from head to foot
十分甜蜜
Delicious, enough.
是真的  对吧
It was real, wasn't it?
我们之间的感情
You and me.
那么久之前  我们还是两个孩子
Such a long time ago, we were just a couple of kids.
但我们真的爱过彼此  对吗
But we really loved each other, didn't we?
我该走了
I should go.
再见
Goodbye.
你明天早上能来一趟吗
Do you think you could back tomorrow morning?
我想带你去看个地方
There's someplace I'd like to show you.
求你了
Please.
-好吧  -那好
- Okay. - Okay.
她如一团烈火回到了他的生命中
She had come back into his life like a sudden flame...
燃烧着流入他心中
...blazing and streaming into his heart.
诺亚整夜未眠
Noah stayed up all night...
想着如果再次失去她
...contemplating the certain agony he knew would be his...
他会多么痛苦
...if he were to lose her twice.
我真希望我知道结局是怎么样的
Oh, I do wish I could figure out the end of this story.
孩子们来了
The children are here.
孩子
Children?
不是你的  他的
Not yours, his.
-见见他们吗  -我很乐意
- Do you mind? - Oh, I'd love to meet them.
过来吧
Come over here.
-爸爸  -亲爱的  你好啊
- Hi, Daddy. - Sweetheart, how are you?
-爸爸  -玛姬
- Hi, Daddy. - Hi, Maggie.
你们好  我是艾莉
Hi, I'm Allie.
-你好  我是玛丽·艾伦  -你好
- Hi, I'm Mary Allen. - Mary Allen.
-见到你很高兴  -我也是
- Nice to see you. - Nice to see you.
你好  我是玛姬
Hi. Maggie.
玛姬  你好啊
Maggie, how are you?
-你好啊  亲爱的  -黛文妮
- Hello there, honey. - Hi. Davanee.
-真好听  -谢谢
- What a pretty name. - Thank you.
天呐  谢谢你
Oh, my, thank you.
-这是谁  -埃德蒙
- And who's this? - Edmond.
你好  埃德蒙
Hi, Edmond.
我想上去
You know, I think I'll run on up...
睡个下午觉  好吗
...and take my afternoon nap, all right?
-走吧  我们走  -去吧
- Come on, honey, let's go. - There you go.
-好了  走吧  -谢谢
- All right. Good. - Thank you.
我回头再继续给你读
I'll read some more later.
好  谢谢
All right, thank you.
见到你们很高兴
I'm so happy to meet you all.
-再见  -再见
- Goodbye. - Bye-bye.
-见到你很高兴  -再见
- Nice to meet you. - Goodbye.
再见
Bye.
-她今天看起来不错  -是啊
- She seems good today. She is good.
今天有点特别
I don't know, there's something about today.
或许是奇迹出现的日子
Maybe it's a day for a miracle.
爸爸
Daddy...
回家吧
...come home.
妈妈不认识我们了
Mama doesn't know us.
她根本不认得你  她不会理解的
She doesn't recognize you. She'll never understand.
我们很想你
We miss you.
你不该住在这儿
This is crazy, you living here.
我们都会来帮助妈妈
you know, we'll all help with Mom.
我们可以轮番来看她
We can take shifts visiting.
听我说
Look, guys.
那可是我的爱人
That's my sweetheart in there.
我不会丢下她的
I'm not leaving her.
这里现在是我的家了
This is my home now.
你们妈妈就是我的家
Your mother is my home.
-喂  -是我
- Hello? - Hey there.
是谁啊
Who is this?
朗啊  你以为是谁
It's Lon, who were you expecting?
没谁
Uh, ha, nobody, I...
我就是有点意外  你怎么找到我的
I just... I'm just surprised. How did you find me?
溪镇只有一家旅馆
Well, there's only one hotel in Seabrook.
你不打电话来  我有点担心
And when you didn't call, I got worried.
你去哪了  你还好吗
Where you been? Are you all right?
我觉得自己好傻
You know, I feel like an idiot,
我给你旅馆打了一百多次了
because I called your hotel about a hundred times.
我没事
I'm fine.
-有什么想跟我说的吗  -没有
- Anything you want to tell me? - No.
-没吗  -嗯
- No? - No.
好吧
Okay.
朗  我爱你
Lon, I love you.
明天打给你
Call you tomorrow?
好
Okay.
诺亚
Noah?
Noah!
你好啊
Hey there.
快走吧  要下雨了
Well, we better get going, the rain's coming in.
-喜欢吗  -真美
- You like it? - It's spectacular.
简直像是梦境
It's like a dream.
-想喂他们吗  -嗯
- Do you wanna feed them? - Yeah.
他们怎么会聚在这儿
What are they all doing here?
不知道
I don't know.
他们早该迁徙去危地马拉的
They're supposed to migrate to Guatemala sound.
不会留在这儿吗
They won't stay here?
不
No.
他们会回家去
They'll go back where they came from.
你变了
You're different.
什么意思
What do you mean?
就是你的样子  一切都变了
Just the way you look. Everything.
你也变了  不过是变好了
You look different too, but in a good way.
其实  你也是
You know, you're kind of the same though.
是吗
Yeah?
嗯
Yeah.
而且你做到了
And you really did it.
-什么  -一切
- What? - Everything.
房子
The house.
你翻修得真漂亮
It's beautiful, what you did.
我向你保证过嘛
Well, I promised you I would.
这下可好
Great.
我们得走了
We gotta go.
诺亚
Noah!
你为什么不给我写信
Why didn't you write me?
为什么
Why?
我当时还爱着你
It wasn't over for me.
我等了你七年
I waited for you for seven years.
现在太晚了
And now it's too late.
我给你写了365封信
I wrote you 365 letters.
每天都写  写了一年
I wrote you every day for a year.
-你写了  -对
- You wrote me? - Yes.
你
You...
当时没有结束
It wasn't over.
现在也没有
It still isn't over.
你开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
等了这么久  这就完了
All this time, that's what I been missing?
再来一次吧
Let's do it again.
诺亚
Noah.
醒醒
Wake up.
醒过来啦
你得要我命了  小姐
You're trying to kill me, woman.
我得休息会儿
I need rest.
我得吃东西  好恢复力气
I need food so I can regain my strength.
好吧  想吃什么
Okay, what do you want?
煎薄饼
Um, some pancakes.
好
Okay.
还有培根
And some bacon.
-好  -鸡肉
- Okay. - And some chicken.
就是她  对吗
She's the one, isn't she?
我能见见她吗
Can I meet her?
我真的很想见她
I'd really like to meet her.
我觉得那样不太好  玛莎
I don't know if that's a good idea, Martha.
这就是玛莎吗
So this is Martha?
你好  我是艾莉
Hi, I'm Allie.
我听说了不少你的事
I've heard a lot about you.
我也是
I've heard a lot about you too.
要进来吗
You want to come in?
-真的吗  -嗯
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
嗯  诺亚刚刚还说他饿了呢
Yeah, Noah was just saying how hungry he was.
你可以去煮壶茶
And, you know, you could put on a pot of tea.
进来吧
Come on in.
Come on.
见到你很高兴  玛莎
It was nice meeting you, Martha.
-我也是  -再见
- Nice meeting you too. - Goodbye.
保重
Take care.
她可真不一般
She's sensational.
真的
She really is.
我很高兴我过来了  诺亚
I'm really glad that I came, Noah.
我都忘了那种感觉了
I'd forgotten what it's like.
理查德死后  我第一次...
For the first time since I lost Richard...
觉得自己有盼头了
...I feel like I've got something to look forward to.
你睡得好安详          不忍心叫醒你
去弄早餐了         就回来
跟着箭头走     有惊喜
朗正在赶过来
Lon is on his way here.
你父亲跟他说了诺亚的事
I'm afraid your father spilled the beans about Noah.
昨晚他又联系不上你
When Lon didn't hear from you last night...
-就决定过来一趟  -好啊
- ...he decided to come. - Well, that's great.
太好了
That's just terrific.
你  我  诺亚  朗  一个快乐的大家庭
You, me, Noah and Lon, one big happy family.
那些信是怎么回事  妈妈
Tell me about the letters, Mother.
-是真的吗  -对
- ls it true? - Yes.
你看着我几个月来哭着入睡
You watched me cry myself to sleep for months and months...
你什么都没说
...and you never said anything.
-你怎么能这么做  -对不起
- How could you do that? - I'm sorry.
-对不起  你对不起  -对  我很抱歉
- You're sorry? You're sorry? - Yes, I am sorry.
就因为你  我这辈子都毁了
Because of you, my entire life is ruined!
好吧  是  我偷了你的信
Okay, yes, I stole your letters.
那的确不对  但你也别闹了
It was wrong, but stop being dramatic
至少承担点责任
and at least take some of the responsibility.
你跑来这儿
You came down here.
你心里很清楚  事情会走到这一步
You knew what you were doing. You knew this would happen.
那么我还成荡妇了
Oh, so now I'm a tramp?
你真是难以置信
You are unbelievable.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
去穿上点衣服
Go on and get some clothes on.
我们去转转
Let's take a drive.
去转转  我为什么要跟你走
Let's take a drive? Why would I want to go anywhere with you?
因为  我比你想的要了解你
Because I might know you a little better than you think.
我不希望你哪天早上醒来
I don't want you waking up one morning...
心想如果早知今日
...thinking if you'd known everything,
何必当初
you might have done something different.
我们来这儿干什么  妈妈
What are we doing here, Mama?
你看到那个男人了吗
Do you see that man, there?
现在看来不像  但25年前
Doesn't look like it now, but 25 years ago....
天呐  他可真迷死个人
Oh, my goodness, he was really something.
我们当时爱得天昏地暗
We were out of our minds in love, let me tell you.
不用说  你外公很生气
Well, naturally, your grandfather was furious...
于是我们决定私奔
...so we decided to run away.
都没走到下座小镇就被警察抓到了
We didn't even make the next town before the police picked us up.
但那是当年了
But that was then.
有时候  我来这一带时
You know, sometimes when I'm in the area...
就会来这儿看他
...I just stop here and I watch him...
想象我的生活本可能是另一番样子
...trying to picture how different my life might have been.
我要告诉你  我爱你父亲
I want you to know that I love your father.
-妈妈  -别插嘴  这很重要
- Mama, I'm... - No, goddamn it, this is important.
你得听我说  我爱他
And you need to hear it. I do.
他是个好男人
He is a wonderful man.
他对我很好  我配不上他
He is good to me and I don't deserve him.
-我爱他  艾莉  真的  -我知道  妈妈
- I love him, Allie, I do, I love him. - I know, Mama.
我知道
I know.
天啊
Oh, God.
真是太丢人了
This is just very embarrassing.
我可真蠢
Oh, I'm a stupid woman.
瞧我  哭得像什么样子
Look at me, the big old bawl-bag.
真是疯了
It's crazy.
我都认不出那个人了
I don't even know who that person is.
我的天
Oh, boy.
艾莉
Allie!
给
Here.
希望你做出正确的决定
I hope you make the right choice.
早上过得挺有趣
Interesting morning?
嗯
Yeah.
朗来了
Lon's here in town.
来这儿了
He's here?
我们回来时看到他的车了
Yeah, we saw his car on the way.
在旅馆
At the hotel.
你收到我的信了
I see you got my letters.
终于
Finally.
你要怎么办  艾莉
What are you gonna do, Al?
我不知道
I don't know.
又回到这样了
We're back to that?
我们又回去了吗
Are we back there?
过去几天怎么说  那都是已经发生了的
What about the past couple of days? They happened, you know.
这我知道  而且这几天很美好
I know that they happened, and they were wonderful.
但也很不负责任
But they were also very irresponsible.
我的未婚夫正在旅馆等着我  等他得知一切
I have a fiance waiting for me at a hotel who's gonna be crushed...
-会伤心欲绝  -你跟我做爱
- ...when he finds out... - So you make love to me...
然后又回到你丈夫身边吗
...and then you go back to your husband?
你就这么打算的吗
Was that your plan?
是我没通过什么测试吗
Was that a test that I didn't pass?
不  我给了他承诺
No. I made a promise to a man.
他给了我一枚戒指  而我承诺了他
He gave me a ring, I gave him my word.
你的承诺现在不已经
Your word is shot to hell now...
-打破了吗  -我不知道  我不知道
- ...don't you think? - I don't know. I don't know.
我跟他谈过之后就会知道了
I'll find out when I talk to him.
这不是在于你是不是遵守承诺
This is not about keeping your promise.
也不是在于顺从你的心
And it's not about following your heart.
-是为了安全感  -什么意思
- It's about security. - What is that supposed to mean?
-钱  -你说什么...
- Money! - What are you ta...?
-他很有钱  -我恨你  你个自大的混蛋
- He's got a lot of money. - Now I hate you, you smug bastard.
我也恨你  如果你走  我就恨你
Well, I hate you. If you leave here, I hate you.
你真的注意到发生了什么事了吗
Have you been paying attention to anything that's happening?
看来没有  我一定是误解了一切信号
I guess not, I think I must have misread all of those signals.
我看也是
I guess you did.
你觉得无聊  你自己也清楚
You're bored. You're bored and you know it.
如果你不是觉得少了什么也不会来了
You wouldn't be here if there wasn't something missing.
你个自大的混蛋
You arrogant son of a bitch!
你能留下吗
Would you just stay with me?
留下  为什么
Stay with you? What for?
-看看我们  已经在吵架了  -我们就这样
- Look at us, we're already fighting. - Well, that's what we do.
我们吵架
We fight.
你说我自大  混蛋
You tell me when I'm being an arrogant son of a bitch...
我说你好烦人
...and I tell you when you're being a pain in the ass.
你绝大部分时候的确很烦人
Which you are, 99 percent of the time.
我不担心会伤到你的感情
I'm not afraid to hurt your feelings.
反正2秒钟就会恢复过来
They have like a two-second rebound rate...
你又继续干烦人的事了
...and you're back doing the next pain-in-the-ass thing.
-所以呢  -所以  不会很轻松的
- So, what? - So it's not gonna be easy.
会很艰难
It's gonna be really hard.
我们每天都得解决这些问题
We're gonna have to work at this every day...
但我想这么做  因为我想要你
...but I want to do that, because I want you.
我要全部的你  直到永远
I want all of you, forever.
你和我  每一天
You and me, every day.
你能帮我个忙吗
Will you do something for me?
你能想象一下你的生活吗
Please? Will you just picture your life for me?
30  40年之后的样子
Thirty years from now, 40 years from now, what's it look like?
如果是跟他在一起  去吧
If it's with that guy, go!
走吧
Go!
我失去过你一次  我还能再做一次
I lost you once, I think I could do it again...
如果那真的是你想要的
...if I thought it's what you really wanted.
但你不许回避问题  选择轻松的路
But don't you take the easy way out.
轻松  哪里轻松了
What easy way? There is no easy way.
不管我怎么做  总会有人受伤
No matter what I do, somebody gets hurt.
你能不能别去考虑别人想怎么样
Would you stop thinking about what everyone wants?
别去考虑我想要什么
Stop thinking about what I want.
他想要什么  你父母想要什么
What he wants, what your parents want.
你想要什么
What do you want?
-你想要什么  -没那么简单
- What do you want? - It's not that simple.
-你想要什么  -没那么...
- What do you want? - It's not...
该死的  你想要什么
Goddamn it, what do you want?
我得走了
I have to go.
最亲爱的艾莉
My dearest Allie.
我昨晚无法入睡
I couldn't sleep last night
因为我知道我们之间已经结束
because I know that it's over between us.
我不再心怀怨念  因为我知道我们的爱是真的
I'm not bitter anymore, because I know that what we had was real.
如果在遥远的未来
And if in some distant place in the future
我们看到了过着新人生的彼此
we see each other in our new lives...
我会对你露出开心的笑容
...I'll smile at you with joy...
记起那个树荫下与你共度的夏天
...and remember how we spent a summer beneath the trees...
通过彼此领悟人生  在爱情中成长
...learning from each other and growing in love.
溪镇旅馆
最美好的爱情  能唤醒人的灵魂
The best love is the kind that awakens the soul...
让我们去寻求更多
...and makes us reach for more.
在我们心中种下火种
That plants a fire in our hearts...
给心灵带来安宁
...and brings peace to our minds.
这就是你所给我的
And that's what you've given me.
希望你也永远能获得这些
That's what I'd hoped to give to you forever.
我爱你  我们来日再见了  诺亚
I love you. I'll be seeing you. Noah.
真美  好美的故事
It's beautiful. It's a beautiful story.
是啊
Yes, it is.
不知道  但这故事让我好伤感
I don't know why, but it makes me feel sad.
我知道你现在觉得茫然若失
I know you feel lost right now...
但别担心
...but don't worry.
没有什么会被真正遗忘
Nothing is ever lost, or can be lost
《持续性》惠特曼
肉体会变得迟缓  衰老  冰冷
The body, sluggish, aged, cold
大火燃烧留下的余烬
The embers left from earlier fires
也会重燃
Shall duly flame again
这是你写的吗
Did you write that?
不是  是沃尔特·惠特曼
No, that was Walt Whitman.
我好像知道他
I think I knew him.
我想是的
I think you did.
我们进去吧  我有点冷了
Shall we go in? I'm feeling a little chilly.
好
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是谁弄的啊
Well, who did all of this?
是我  我护理人员的朋友也帮了忙
I did, with a little help from my friends on the nursing staff.
我从没见过这么美的景色
I've never seen anything so beautiful.
我也是
Neither have l.
我们入座吧
Shall we?
-来点葡萄汁  -好啊
- Some grape juice? - I'd love it.
好多药丸啊  你病得很重吗
Ah, so many pills. How sick are you?
对我而言  病已经是个相对概念了
Sickness has become a relative term for me.
我现在更多把它看成是消耗的过程
I think of it now as more a general wearing-out process.
敬你
To you.
结局呢
So, what happened?
故事的结局
In the story.
她选了谁
Which one did she choose?
好吧
Okay.
那么  我有三个选择
The way I see it, I got three choices.
一  我毙了他
One, I can shoot him.
二  我扁死他
Two, I can kick the crap out of him.
三  我离开你
Or three, I leave you.
但这些都不好
But all that's no good.
因为
You see, because...
这些选择都无法让我得到你
...none of those options get me you.
尽管发生的一切
And in spite of everything...
我还是爱你
...I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
我给你戒指的时候  说的话都是真心的
I meant what I said when I gave you that ring.
我也是
I did too.
真的  但是我...
I did too. It's just that when I'm...
我跟诺亚在一起的时候  那种感觉
When I'm with Noah I feel like one person...
跟和你在一起的时候完全不一样
...and when I'm with you I feel like someone totally different.
无法忘记初恋是很正常的
Look, it's normal not to forget your first love.
我爱你  艾莉
I love you, Allie.
但我想要你
But I want you for myself.
我不想还要说服我未婚妻
I don't want to have to convince my fiance...
她该跟我在一起
...that she should be with me.
你不用
You don't have to.
我已经知道我该跟你在一起
I already know I should be with you.
于是他们过上了幸福的生活
And they lived happily ever after.
谁  是谁啊
Who? Who did?
是啊
Oh, yes.
当然了
Of course.
我记得了
I remember now.
是我们
It was us.
-是我们  是我们  -亲爱的
- lt was us. It was us. - Oh, my darling.
我的爱人
Oh, my sweetheart.
我好爱你
I love you so much.
亲爱的
Oh, my baby.
诺亚  诺亚
Noah, Noah.
我爱你  天使
I love you, angel.
-我是怎么了  -没事
- What happened to me? - Nothing.
就是走开了一下
You just went away for a little while.
-我们还有多久  -不好说
- How much time do we have? - I'm not sure.
上次不到五分钟
Last time it was no more than five minutes.
好吧
Okay.
我带了个老朋友来
Hey, I brought along an old friend.
-孩子们怎么样了  -他们很好
- How are the children? - Oh, they're fine.
他们今天还来了呢
Yeah, they were here today.
还有小诺亚和黛文妮
Little Noah, Davanee too.
他们长得好大了
They're getting so big.
天呐
Oh, boy.
时光飞逝啊
How fast the time goes.
-一眨眼就过去了  -是啊
- It flies right on by. - Oh, yes, it does.
代我告诉他们我爱他们
Will you tell them I love them?
当然
Of course I will.
还有我很抱歉
And that I'm sorry.
我会说的  亲爱的
I'll tell them, sweetheart.
记得你读给我听的那个故事吗
Remember that story you were reading to me?
嗯
Yes.
你说我今晚能做她吗
Do you think that I could be her tonight?
那样行吗
Would that be all right?
你知道我们能干什么吗
You know what we could do?
或许我们可以弄辆车  去兜兜风
Maybe we could get a car and we could go for a ride.
我们离开这里  随便去哪  你想去吗
We could get out of here and just go someplace, you want to?
还是算了  今晚不行  亲爱的
I don't think so. Not tonight, darling.
为什么不呢
Come on, why not?
等等
Wait a minute.
你为什么喊我亲爱的  我不认识你
Why did you call me darling? I don't know you.
怎么回事  我认识你吗
What's going on here? Am I supposed to know you?
-艾莉  艾莉  亲爱的  -不要
- Allie. Allie, sweetheart. - No, no, no!
艾莉  我爱你  别走开  留在我身边
Hey, Allie, I love you, stay with me, don't leave...
不要
No!
你是谁
Who are you?
我是诺亚  我是诺亚  你是艾莉
I'm Noah, I'm Noah and you're Allie.
你想怎么样  你在这儿干什么
What do you want? What are you doing here?
-别这样  亲爱的  -别靠近我
- Come on, baby. - Don't come near me!
-别过来  -艾莉  艾莉  我...
- Don't you come near me! - Allie... Allie, I...
救命啊
Help! Help!
-救救我  -冷静点  艾莉  冷静
- Help me! - Calm down, Allie, calm down.
-不  不要你  -冷静点  艾莉  没事的
- No, not you! - Calm down, Allie! It's all right, come on.
-不  放开我  -冷静点  没事的
- No! Let me go! - It's all right. Calm down.
-不  放开我  -冷静下来  艾莉  没事的
- No! Leave me alone. - Calm down, Allie, it's all right.
-谁救救我啊  -冷静下来
- Somebody help me! - Now calm down.
-救命  -医生
- Help! - Doctor!
-怎么回事  -她产生幻觉了
- Talk to me. - She's sundowning.
-谁救救我啊  -冷静点
- Somebody help me! - Calm down!
-给她两个单位  -不要
- Give her two cc's. - No! No!
-冷静点  艾莉  -一  二  三
- Calm down, Allie. - One, two, three.
-好了  艾莉  没事的  -好了  没事了
- Allie, it's all right. It's all right. - Okay, okay, okay.
我来看一眼
Okay, now take a look.
让我看看  她没事了
Let's take a look. One. Oh, she's fine.
-好  呼吸  -她没事了  没事了
- Good. Just breathe. - She's fine. She's fine.
冷静下来  呼吸  没事了
Stay calm, just breathe in and out, come on.
-放松  -你没事的  艾莉
- Relax. - You're gonna be okay, Allie.
-放松  -艾莉
- Relax. - Allie?
你没事  亲爱的
You're fine, honey.
我们人生的故事
艾莉森·汉密尔顿·卡尔霍恩著
致吾爱诺亚
读给我听
我就会回到你身边
早啊  卡尔霍恩先生
Morning, Mr. Calhoun.
卡尔霍恩先生
Mr. Calhoun?
打给南卡罗莱纳医科大学的冯·佩蒂特医生
Call Dr. Von Pettit, MUSC, okay?
没有血压  没有脉搏  什么都没有
I've got no BP, I got no pulse. I've got nothing.
告诉他们已经心脏停搏  打我手机找我
Let them know we're in full arrest. Call me on my cell.
好的
Okay, will do.
我们说过的
We talked about this.
没事了  走吧  亲爱的
It's all right now. Come on, come on, precious.
来吧  进来吧
Okay, yes, come on, let's go.
没事的  亲爱的  来吧
It's okay, baby, come on.
你认识霍姆斯先生的
You know Mr. Holmes.
卡尔霍恩先生
Oh, Mr. Calhoun.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
-你感觉怎么样  -很好  可好了
- How do you feel? - Fine. Fit as a fiddle.
-你要去哪  -就是去散散步
- Where you going? - I was just taking a walk.
睡不着
I can't sleep.
你知道这样不行  违反规定
Well, you know you're not supposed to, it's against the rules.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
你不是要去散步吧
You weren't really going for a walk, were you?
你想去见艾莉小姐
You were going to see Miss Allie.
我刚刚出院
I just got out of the hospital.
我想她了
And I miss her.
卡尔霍恩先生
Mr. Calhoun.
抱歉  但我今晚不能让你去看她
I'm sorry, but I can't let you see her tonight.
你得回你房间
Now you're gonna have to go back to your room.
至于我
As for me...
我要下楼给自己弄杯咖啡
...I'm gonna go downstairs and get myself a cup of coffee.
我要过好一会儿才能回来查房
I won't be back to check on you for a while.
所以别做什么傻事
So don't do anything foolish.
诺亚
Noah.
亲爱的
Hi, sweetheart.
很抱歉我都没能在这儿给你读书
I'm sorry I haven't been able to be here to read to you.
我不知道该怎么办
I didn't know what to do.
我还担心你不会回来了
I was afraid you were never coming back.
我总会回来的
I'll always come back.
如果有一天
What's gonna happen...
我什么都不记得了  会怎么样
...when I can't remember anything anymore?
你要怎么办
What will you do?
我还会在这儿
Oh, I'll be here.
我永远不会抛下你
I'll never leave you.
我有个问题
I need to ask you something.
说吧  亲爱的
What is it, sweetheart?
你觉得
Do you think...
我们的爱
...that our love...
能创造奇迹吗
...can create miracles?
我相信能
Yes, I do.
就是奇迹让你总能回到我身边
That's what brings you back to me each time.
你觉得我们的爱
Do you think our love...
能带我们一起离开吗
...could take us away together?
我觉得我们的爱  无所不能
I think our love can do anything we want it to.
我爱你
I love you.
我爱你  艾莉
I love you, Allie.
晚安
Good night.
我们来世再见了
I'll be seeing you.